<section id="ug_project_docman">
	<title>Document Manager</title>
	<para>
		The Document Manager provided with FusionForge gives you a simple way to publish documents on the site. 
	</para>
	<section id="ug_project_docman_submit_new">
		<title>Submit new documentation</title>
		<para>
			Here you can submit new documents for approving/publishing on the site. The form requires you to insert the following information:
		</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Document Title</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The document title refers to the relatively brief title of the document</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Description</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A brief description to be placed just under the title.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Upload File</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Here you should select the file to be uploaded. You can upload text files (.html, .txt) or binary files (.zip, .doc, .pdf).</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Reference File (by an URL)</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Instead of uploading a file, you can specify the URL where the document is located.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Language</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>You should select here the language of the document.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Group that document belongs in</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>You should select here the group of the document. This feature is used to categorize documents.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<para>
			Fill in all the fields, select the group from the drop down list and click <guimenuitem>Submit Information</guimenuitem>. The document will then be placed in the <guimenuitem>Pending Submissions</guimenuitem> section of the <guimenuitem>DocManager Admin</guimenuitem> page, to be approved or rejected.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="ug_project_docman_view_existing">
		<title>Viewing existing docs</title>
		<para>
			The View Documentation page shows you a list of documents published and approved for viewing; grouped by Document groups. You can click on a document to view the entire content.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="ug_project_docman_admin">
		<title>Admin</title>
		<para>
			Clicking on this will present you with a page showing pending and active documents. In order to allow users to submit a document, you must first set up the document groups for the project.
		</para>
		<para>
			The Admin section allows you to:
		</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Approve/publish pending submissions</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The Pending Submissions list shows the list of submissions that are waiting for your approval. Clicking on the document name, the Edit Document form will be displayed.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Edit Documents</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The Edit Document links shows all states of the documents, and the documents in the state:</para>
					<variablelist>
						<varlistentry>
							<term>Active Documents</term>
							<listitem>
								<para>Active Documents are displayed in the View Documentation list.</para>
							</listitem>
						</varlistentry>
						<varlistentry>
							<term>Pending Documents</term>
							<listitem>
								<para>Pending Documents are waiting for your approval.</para>
							</listitem>
						</varlistentry>
						<varlistentry>
							<term>Hidden Documents</term>
							<listitem>
								<para>Hidden documents are not displayed.</para>
							</listitem>
						</varlistentry>
						<varlistentry>
							<term>Deleted Documents</term>
							<listitem>
								<para>Deleted Documents are old, outdated documents.</para>
							</listitem>
						</varlistentry>
						<varlistentry>
							<term>Private Documents</term>
							<listitem>
								<para>Private documents are displayed only for members of the project.</para>
							</listitem>
						</varlistentry>
					</variablelist>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Edit Document Groups</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Clicking on this will present you with a box and a button to add document groups, and it also shows the document groups associated with this project. Submit as many document categories as you wish - eg Howto, Release notes, FAQ, etc. These groups will be the categories the documents will fall into when users submit documents.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section id="ug_project_docman_edit">
		<title>Edit Document</title>
		<para>
			When you select a document from one of the lists, a form will be displayed. In this form you can change the Document Title, the Short Description, the Language, the Document Group and the State.
		</para>
		<para>
			If the Document is a text file with .txt, .html or .htm extension, a textbox appears where you can edit the content of the document.
		</para>
		<para>
			If the Document is a binary document, you can upload a new version of the document.
		</para>
	</section>
</section>
