<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="reinhard@spisser.it">Reinhard Spisser</author>
    <title>Gforge User Guide - Document Manager</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

<section name="Document Manager">
<p>
The Document Manager provided with Gforge gives you a simple way to publish documents on the site. 


</p>
</section>
<section name="Submit new documentation">
<p>
Here you can submit new documents for approving/publishing on the site. The form requires you to insert the following information:

<ul>
<li><b>Document Title</b><br/>
The document title refers to the relatively brief title of th document 
</li>
<li><b>Description</b><br/>
A brief description to be placed just under the title.
</li>
<li><b>Upload File</b><br/>
Here you should select the file to be uploaded. You can upload text files (.html, .txt) or binary files (.zip, .doc, .pdf).
</li>
<li><b>Language</b><br/>
You should select here the language of the document.
</li>
<li><b>Group that document belongs in:</b><br/>
You should select here the group of the document.
</li>

Fill in all the fields, select the group from the drop down list and click 
<b>Submit Information</b>. The document will then be placed in the <b>Pending 
Submissions</b> section of the <b>DocManager Admin</b> page, to be approved 
or rejected.


</ul>


</p>
</section>
<section name="Viewing existing docs">
<p>
The viewing existing docs shows you a list of documents published and approved for viewing; grouped by Document groups. You can click on a document to view the entire content.


</p>
</section>
<section name="Admin Doc">
<p>

Clicking on this will present you with a page showing pending and active 
documents.  In order to 
allow users to submit a document, you must first set up the document groups 
for the project.

The Admin section allows you to:

<ol>
<li><b>Approve/publish pending submissions</b><br/>
The Pendig Submissions list shows the list of submissions that are waiting for your approval.<br/>
Clicking on the Document name, the Edit Document form will be displayed.

</li>
<li><b>Edit Documents</b><br/>
The Edit Document links shows all states of the documents, and the documents in the state:
<ul>
<li><b>Active Documents</b><br/>
Active Documents are displayed in the View Documentation list
</li>
<li><b>Pending Documents</b><br/>
Pending Documents are waiting for your approval.
</li>
<li><b>Hidden Documents</b><br/>
</li>
<li><b>Deleted Documents</b><br/>
Deleted Documents are old, outdated documents.
</li>
<li><b>Private Documents</b><br/>

</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><b>Edit Document Groups</b><br/>
Clicking on this will present you with a box and a button to add document 
groups, and it also shows the document groups associated with this project. 
Submit as many document classes as you wish - eg Howto, Release notes, FAQ, 
etc. These groups will be the catagories the documents will fall into when 
users submit documents.

</li>
</ol>

</p>
</section>
<section name="Edit Document">
<p>
When you select a document from one of the lists, a form will be displayed. In this form you can change the Document Title, the Short Description, the Language, the Document Group and the State.
<br/>
If the Document is a text file with .txt, .html or .htm extension, a textbox appreas where you can edit the content of the document.
<br/>
If the Document is a binary document, you can upload a new version of the document.
</p>
</section>
</body>
</document>
