<section id="ug_project_surveys">
	<title>Surveys</title>
	<section id="ug_project_surveys_introduction">
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<para>
			Surveys allow you to ask questions to your developer/users and view the results. Surveys are often very helpful if you need some feedback from the users, examples of surveys might be:
		</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem><para>User feedback: ask users if they like your project</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Developer feedback: ask developers on new features to be implemented</para></listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>
			Of course, surveys are not limited to this list. Basically, you can ask everything you want with surveys.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="ug_project_surveys_questions">
		<title>Administering survey questions</title>
		<para>
			Before you can add/modify existing surveys, you need to administer the questions for your surveys. Questions are global for all surveys.
		</para>
		<para>
			FusionForge surveys handle the following question types:
		</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Radio Buttons 1-5: This type of question shows 5 radio buttons where the user can select between 1 (low) and 5 (high).</para>
				<para>This is useful for indicating priorities or quality feedback (e.g.: the question might be: did you like the new xxx feature. The user can select (1 (not very much), 2,3,4, 5(really)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem><para>Radio Buttons Yes/No. This type of question allows only two choices: Yes or No.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Comment Only</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Text field: This type of question allows the user to insert some text in a text field.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Text area: This type of question allows the user to insert some text in a textarea</para></listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>
			When inserting new questions or modifying existing questions, take note of the ID of the question. You'll need them when creating/modifying surveys.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="ug_project_surveys_create_new">
		<title>Creating a new survey</title>
		<para>
			You can create a new survey by clicking on the <guimenuitem>Admin</guimenuitem> link and then <guimenuitem>Add a new survey</guimenuitem>.
		</para>
		<para>You'll be asked to insert the following data:</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Survey name</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The name of the survey</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Question list</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Here you should insert the IDs of the questions in the order they should appear. If you wish to see question 4 first, then question 6, then question 1, you should insert here 4,6,1.</para>
					<warning>
						<para>Don't insert spaces or any character other than comma between the numbers.</para>
					</warning>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Is Active?</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>This flag indicates if the survey is active or not.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	<section id="ug_project_surveys_modification">
		<title>Modifying a survey</title>
		<para>
			You can modify an existing survey, although this is not recommended if answers to the survey have already been given.
		</para>
		<para>
			You should know that the results of a survey are not consistent if you modify the survey and users have already inserted answers.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="ug_project_surveys_results">
		<title>Viewing survey results</title>
		<para>
			If you have admin rights, you can view the results of the surveys clicking on the <guimenuitem>View Results</guimenuitem> tab.
		</para>
		<para>
                        You can export the survey results in a file in CSV format. This file can then be
                        imported in a spreadsheet like Open Office Calc or Microsoft Excel.
		</para>
	</section>
</section>
